A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Publications FA767
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation publications, 1936-2010; 1
  - The Garden of the Ford Foundation Building, by Dan Kiley, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 510)
  - Ford Foundation Building Dedication Ceremonies, 1967 December (Box 41, Folder 511)
    Includes material related to the dedication of the Ford Foundation's new headquarters building in New York.
  - Ford Foundation Confidential Directory of Trustees, Officers, and Senior Staff (U.S. and Overseas), 2004-2006 (Box 41, Folder 512)
  - Ford Foundation Annual Reports' "President's Review" excerpts and reprints, 1959-2001 (Box 41, Folder 513)
  - The Ford Foundation in the State(s) of?., 1957-1959 (Box 42, Folder 514)
    Series of booklets highlighting the Ford Foundation's work in specific U.S. states, or groups of states.
  - Ford Foundation Activities in Japan, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 515)
  - Ford Foundation Program in North Africa, 1964-1974 (Box 42, Folder 516)
  - Ford Foundation in Eastern and Southern Africa / Ford Foundation in East and Central Africa, 1964-1980 (Box 42, Folder 517)
  - Ford Foundation Assistance in West and Central Africa, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 518)
  - Ford Foundation Assistance in the Arab Middle East and North Africa, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 519)
  - Ford Foundation Program in the United Arab Republic, 1964-1968 (Box 42, Folder 520)
  - Ford Foundation Program in Iraq, Jordan, Lebanon, Saudi Arabia, and Syria, 1962-1964 (Box 42, Folder 521)
  - Ford Foundation Program in Nigeria, 1965 (Box 42, Folder 522)
  - The Ford Foundation in Turkey, 1952-1967 (Box 42, Folder 523)
  - Ford Foundation in Malaysia and Singapore, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 524)
  - Ford Foundation in Colombia, 1965 (Box 42, Folder 525)
  - Ford Foundation Program in Argentina, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 526)
  - Ford Foundation - Andean Region and the Southern Cone, 1980s (Box 42, Folder 527)
  - Ford Foundation Program in Burma, 1953-1958 (Box 42, Folder 528)
  - Ford Foundation Program in Peru, 1972-1974 (Box 42, Folder 529)
  - The Ford Foundation in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 530)
  - Ford Foundation - program pamphlets, 1970s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 531)
  - Ford Foundation - program pamphlets, 1960-1962 (Box 42, Folder 532)
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Resources and Environment, 1968-1978 (Box 43, Folder 533)
    Program pamphlets.
  - Ford Foundation Program in Humanities and the Arts, 1957-1959 (Box 43, Folder 534)
  - Ford Foundation - general pamphlets, 1950s-1990s (Box 43, Folder 535, 536)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, A-B (Box 43, Folder 537)
    Reprints of articles, editorials, essays, and speeches published by Ford Foundation officers and staff in journals, magazines, and newspapers. Arranged A-Z by author.
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, McGeorge Bundy (Box 43, Folder 538)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, C-E (Box 43, Folder 539)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, F (Box 43, Folder 540)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, G (Box 44, Folder 541)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, H (Box 44, Folder 542)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, Oscar Harkavy (Box 44, Folder 543)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, Harold Howe II (Box 44, Folder 544)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, J (Box 44, Folder 545)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, K (Box 44, Folder 546)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, L (Box 44, Folder 547)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, M (Box 44, Folder 548)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, N-R (Box 44, Folder 549)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, S (Box 44, Folder 550)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, Francis X. Sutton (Box 45, Folder 551)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, T (Box 45, Folder 552)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, Franklin A. Thomas (Box 45, Folder 553)
  - Ford Foundation officer and staff reprints, W, X, Y, Z (Box 45, Folder 554)
  - Rural India in Transition, by Douglas Ensminger, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 555)
    Published by All India Panchayat Parishad, printed in India.
  - A Guide to Community Development [in India], by Douglas Ensminger, 1957 (Box 45, Folder 556)
    Includes typed note from Ensminger to John B. Howard, "This is the Foundation's most recent non-grant contribution to the people of India. I wrote this for the Ministry of Community Development". Issued by the Ministry of Community Development, Government of India.
  - Conquest of World Hunger and Poverty, by Douglas Ensminger and Paul Bomani, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 557)
    Includes manuscript note from Ensminger to Franklin A. Thomas, June 1980. Published by Iowa Sate University Press/Ames.
  - Agriculture in India, volume I - General (Bengali edition), 1960 (Box 45, Folder 558)
    Authors include Dr. Earl N. Moore and Roy L. Donahue, consultants to the Ford Foundation. Related file: Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), 06090083 (PA60-83), PROGRAM SPECIALISTS AND CONSULTANTS FOR INDIA'S FOOD PRODUCTION PROGRAM.
  - Agriculture in India, volume I - General (Gujarati edition), 1960 (Box 45, Folder 559)
  - Ford Foundation, Board of TrusteesÿFutureÿProgramÿPlanningÿProjectÿ, 1976 (Box 46)
    Includes the following sections/chapters: ?The Assets of the Ford Foundation for the 1980s? by McGeorge Bundy; ?Private foundations and governmental attitudes: 1985?; ?Philanthropic choices, style, and methods: a 25-year review?; Vol. 1: The Hungry, Crowded, Competitive World; Vol. 2: Democratic Polity and How it Works, with Special Reference to the United States; Vol. 3: Values, Society, and Culture; Vol. 4: The Generation and Spread of Knowledge and its Application to Change in Society; Vol. 5: Economic Growth and the Distribution of Economic Opportunity and Benefits Among Men and Nations; Vol. 6: Justice, Fairness, and Human Rights; Vol. 7: War, Peace, and Cooperation Among Nations; Vol. 8: The Nature of the Individual and his Fulfillment.
  - Industrialism and Industrial Man in Retrospect: A Critical Review of the Ford Foundation's Support for the Inter-University Study of Labor, by James L. Cochrane, 1979 (Box 46)
    See also Ford Foundation grant PA759-3 (07590003), FISCAL YEARS 1975 TO 1977 TRAVEL AND STUDY GRANTS.
  - The School and the Democratic Environment, 1970 (Box 46)
    Papers and other materials drawn from a conference sponsored by the Danforth Foundation and the Ford Foundation.
  - Adult Illiteracy in the United States: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Carman St. John and David Harman, 1979 (Box 46)
  - Dealing with Drug Abuse: A Report to the Ford Foundation - The Drug Abuse Survey Project, 1972 (Box 46)
  - Adult Literacy and Broadcasting: The BBC's Experience: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by David Hargreaves, 1980 (Box 46)
    See also Ford Foundation grant PA75-426 (07500426), British Broadcasting Corporation.
  - Coming of Age in the Ghetto: A Dilemma of Youth Unemployment: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Garth Mangum and Stephen Seninger, 1978 (Box 46)
    See also Ford Foundation grant PA67-578 (06700578),George Washington University, SUPPORT OF THE CENTER FOR SOCIAL POLICY STUDIES FOR EVALUATIONS OF NATIONAL SOCIAL POLICIES AND PROGRAMS.
  - Crisis in the Workplace: Occupational Disease and Injury: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Nicholas A. Ashford, 1976 (Box 46)
  - Limiting Population Growth and the Ford Foundation Contribution, by John Caldwell and Pat Caldwell, 1986 (Box 46)
  - American Workers Abroad: A Report to the Ford Foundation, edited by Robert Schrank, 1979 (Box 46)
  - Poverty and Malnutrition in Latin America: Early Childhood Intervention Programs: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Ernesto Pollitt, 1980 (Box 46)
  - Growing Up Forgotten: A Review of Research and Programs Concerning Early Adolescence: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Joan Lipsitz, 1977 (Box 46)
  - The Ford Foundation Mid-Decade Review, 1987 (Box 47)
    V. 1. The Ford Foundation: leadership in affecting poverty -- v. 2. Women and children in poverty: reproductive health and child survival -- v. 3. Rural poverty and resource management: a review of foundation activities in agricultural systems, land management, and water management -- v. 4. What ever happened to poverty alleviation? -- v. 5. Encouraging stability, peace, and justice in the international order -- v. 6. The Ford Foundation: program on education and culture -- v. 7. The Ford Foundation: pluralism and diversity.
  - New Patterns for College Lending: Income Contingent Loans: A Ford Foundation Report, by D. Bruce Johnstone, 1972 (Box 47)
    Columbia University Press
  - One Nation, So Many Governments: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Michael N. Danielson, Alan M. Hershey, and John M. Bayne, 1977 (Box 47)
    Lexington Books
  - Many Roads to Justice: The Law Related Work of Ford Foundation Grantees Around the World, 2000 (Box 47)
  - Toward Humanistic Education: A Curriculum of Affect, edited by Gerald Weinstein and Mario D. Fantini, 1970 (Box 47)
  - City High Schools: A Recognition of progress: A Ford Foundation Report, 1984 (Box 47)
  - Different Strokes: Pathways to Maturity in the Boston Ghetto: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Robert Rosenthal, Bernard Bruce, Faith Dunne, and Florence Ladd, 1976 (Box 47)
    Westview Press
  - Rompiendo la Indiferencia: Acciones Ciudadanas en Defensa del Interes Publico (Breaking Indifference: Citizen Action in Defense of Public Interest), circa1980s (Box 47)
    Published by the Ford Foundation Office for the Andean Region and the Southern Cone.
  - The Challenge of Interdependence: Mexico and the United States, 1989 (Box 47)
    Report of the Bilateral Commission on the Future of United Sates-Mexican Relations. See related file: Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (08690550): SUPPORT FOR THE ORGANIZATION AND ACTIVITIES OF A COMMISSION ON U.S.-MEXICAN RELATIONS.
  - Understanding China: An Assessment of American Scholarly Resources: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by John M.H. Lindbeck, 1971 (Box 47)
  - A Fundacao Ford No Brasil (Ford Foundation in Brazil), 1993 (Box 47)
  - PASAA Special Issue, Vol VI, number 1-2, A Festschrift for Richard B. Noss, 1976 October (Box 47)
    PASAA, "notes and news about language teaching and linguistics in Thailand", published in Bangkok, Thailand. See related Ford Foundation grant: Central Institute Of English Language (07450392), SUPPORT FOR PUBLICATION OF COLLECTION OF THAI LINGUISTIC PAPERS.
  - Upasana, Sane Guruji Vidya-Prabodhini, Khiroda, 1973 June (Box 47)
    Includes "Community Education and Training in Integrated Rural Development", by Dr. Eugene Staley. See related Ford Foundation grant: South India Teachers Union Council Of Educational Research (06900204), SUPPORT FOR EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH STUDY.
  - India's Roots of Democracy: A Sociological Analysis of Rural India's Experience in Planned Development Since Independence, by Carl C. Taylor, Douglas Ensminger, Helen W. Johnson, and Jean Joyce, 1965 (Box 47)
  - The Ford Foundation: 40 years in the Andean Region and Southern Cone, 2003 (Box 47)
  - Frontiers in Reproduction and Fertility Control: A Review of the Reproductive Sciences and Contraceptive Development, Part 2, 1977 (Box 47)
    Sponsored by the Ford Foundation. Roy O. Greep, Project Director; Marjorie A. Koblinsky, Assistant Project Director. (Greep Report).
  - Celebrating Indonesia, Fifty years with the Ford Foundation, 1953-2003 (Box 47)
  - Energy and Agriculture in the Third World, by Arjun Makhijani and Alan Poole, 1975 (Box 48)
    A Report to the Energy Policy Project of the Ford Foundation. See related file: Foundation-Administered Project, 07290125 (PA72-125), CLOSE OUT COSTS OF THE ENERGY POLICY PROJECT.
  - Energy Policy: Industry Perspectives, by John E. Gray, 1975 (Box 48)
  - Energy Research and Development, by J. Herbert Hollomon et al., 1975 (Box 48)
  - The Energy Conservation Papers, edited by Robert H. Williams, 1975 (Box 48)
  - Energy Taxes and Subsidies, by Gerard M. Brannon, circa1980s (Box 48)
  - Energy Prices, 1960-1973, by Foster Associates, Inc., circa1980s (Box 48)
  - Oil Spills and the Marine Environment, by Donald F. Boesch, Carl H. Hershner and Jerome H. Milgram, 1974 (Box 48)
  - Competition in the U.S. Energy Industry, by Thomas D. Duchesneau, 1975 (Box 48)
  - Nuclear Theft: Risks and Safeguards, by Mason Willrich and Theodore B. Taylor, 1974 (Box 48)
  - Financing the Energy Industry, by Jerome E. Haas, Edward J. Mitchell, Bernell H. Stone, and David H. Downes, 1974 (Box 48)
  - The American Energy Consumer, by Dorothy K. Newman and Dawn Day, 1975 (Box 48)
  - A Time to Chose: America's Energy Future, 1974 (Box 48)
    Final Report by the Energy Policy Project of the Ford Foundation. See related file: Foundation-Administered Project, 07290125 (PA72-125), CLOSE OUT COSTS OF THE ENERGY POLICY PROJECT.
  - A Debate on 'A Time to Chose': 'A Critique' by William Tavoulareas; 'A Reply' by Carl Kaysen, 1977 (Box 48)
  - Not Well Advised, Peter Szanton, 1981 (Box 48)
    "The City as Client- An Illuminating Analysis of Urban Governments and their Consultants". Published by the Russell Sage Foundation and the Ford Foundation.
  - Welfare: The Elusive Consensus - Where we are, how we got there, and what's ahead, by Lester M. Salamon, 1978 (Box 48)
    A Report from the Welfare Policy Project of the Ford Foundation and Duke University.
  - Employment in Developing Nations, edited by Edgar O. Edwards, 1974 (Box 48)
    A Report on a Ford Foundation Study.
  - Education and Development Reconsidered: The Bellagio Conference Papers, edited by F. Champion Ward, 1974 (Box 48)
    Published by the Ford Foundation and Rockefeller Foundation.
  - Reconnection for Learning - A Community School System for New York City (Report of the Mayor's Advisory Panel on Decentralization of the New York City Schools (Box 49)
  - Higher-Wider-Education - A Report on Open Learning, 1976 (Box 49)
  - Minorities and the Media - A Ford Foundation Report, 1974 (Box 49)
  - Approaches to Arms Control in Europe - A Conference Report by Kerry S. McNamara (Institute for East-West Security Studies, 1984 March (Box 49)
  - Education for Public Responsibility (Fund for Adult Education) (Box 49)
  - Mediating Social Conflict - A Ford Foundation Report, 1978 (Box 49)
  - The Near Side of Federalism - Improving State and Local Government, 1972 January (Box 49)
  - Ford Foundation Pocket Program Guide, 2000 (Box 49)
  - Ford Foundation Good Neighbor Committee, 2000; 4 copies (Box 49)
  - The Challenge of Lifetime Learning (Fund for Adult Education report), 1961 (Box 49)
  - New Options in the Philanthropic Process - A Ford Foundation Statement of Policy, 1968 (Box 49)
  - Report to the PRC, Volume I and II, 1983 July (Box 49)
  - Industrial Literacy Project - Final Report to the Ford Foundation, Grant 790-0266 by Sylvia Schribner, Volume II, 1983 (Box 49)
  - Public Interest Law Around the World (An NAACP-LDF Symposium Report), 1992 (Box 49)
  - A. Fundacao Ford no Brasil - The Ford Foundation in Brazil 1998-1999, 2000 (Box 49)
  - The Fund for Adult Education - Annual Report 1970-1971 (Box 49)
  - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA), Ibadan, Nigeria, 1968 (Box 49)
  - Ford Foundation - Webster's Timeline History, 1932-2007 (Box 49)
  - The Newsman's Scope, 1968 (Box 49)
  - George Washington University, Center for Social Policy Studies - Spending to Save, Expanding Employment Opportunities (Box 49)
  - Taking Up the Challenge - The Promotion of Human Rights, A Guide for the Scientific Community by Kari Hannibal (Science and Human Rights Program, American Association of the Advancement of Science, 1992 (Box 49)
  - Minority Contractor Bonding Program - A Manual of Organizational Steps and Procedures (Division of National Affairs, Ford Foundation) (Box 49)
  - Nuclear Power Issues and Choices - Overview - Excerpt from the Report of the Nuclear Energy Policy Study Group, 1977 (Box 49)
  - Fundacion Ford - Region Andina y Lono Sur (Box 49)
  - Golden Years, 1963 November (Box 49)
  - Minorities in Business - Ford Foundation Assistance, 1965-1975, 1976 June (Box 49)
  - Taconic Foundation Report, 1965 December (Box 49)
  - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, Research Reports - A Comparison of the Effectiveness of Adult Residential and Non-Residential Learning Situations by A. A. Lacognata (Box 49)
  - Metropolis, third printing, 1963; Booklet (Box 49)
  - The New Teacher, second printing, 1962 November; Booklet (Box 49)
  - Mental Health - A Ford Foundation Report, 1958; Booklet (Box 49)
  - The Good Seed, 1957 November; Booklet (Box 49)